<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PBP]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>PBP</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 04:53:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 04:53:00 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[People Be People]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Hello, everyone!<br>I am Shay von Amyprost. If you are reading this it is because you have been wandering around my GitHub repositories, somehow discovered this link or I showed it to you in some way. In any case, be welcome to my wannabe blog!<br>Like many people, it wasn't since always that I question things about life in a society. This doesn't mean that this questioning began a little ago. Quite the opposite, I have been questioning for a while, but never really expressed anything, or only did to a very few and selected people. I want to start doing precisely that.<br>It is always better to have some people to talk to. In that line of thought, it would be better to have some sort of podcast. However, I do know myself enough to know that I like to rant (I tend to record and send relatively long audio messages). For this reason, I think this blog will be my way to go, for the time being.<br>If I have sent you the link to this blog, showed or presented it in a way that not everyone can see, feel free to contact me as you prefer, in case you want to discuss or talk about any topic that I write here. If you somehow managed to get this link somehow else, as described earlier, well... hold that thought! I will think of an "official" way of contacting me, so that I can have all of the comments specifically about this blog in one single place.<br>Without further ado, here is People Be People! :D]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:48:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Some thoughts on December holidays]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>On 25th of December, 2024. At 12:30.<br>If you already know me, you would know that I am not a Christian. There are some thoughts on that topic, but that is not the topic of this "entry". I was a Christian, a Catholic, for the most part of my childhood and teenage years. I was aware that Christmas is the holiday to celebrate the birth of Jesus Christ, but we all know the tradition in which the main part of this holiday, especially for children, are gifts.<br>Every year, everything that gave meaning to Christmas were rather the gifts left under the tree by Saint Nicholas, and sure enough I would be thrilled to open them up ad receive some toys from my family as well. Nowadays, as an agnostic, I do understand how important this holiday is supposed to be. And just as how I'm not bothered by having a day when I receive gifts, I'm also not bothered by just receiving them. I do appreciate them, but a part of me feels out of place when I see all of the decorations and the "special cooking" and think that the reason is something that I don't believe in anymore. So, I'll say it straight: Christmas has lost its meaning to me.<br>Sure, in many different cultures there is some kind of celebration around the same dates or during December, but now I don't have any particular reason to celebrate. Let's say I'd still do it for the gifts. Do we need a specific day to give anyone a gift or a small present? In any case, knowing that there is a specific date for it, you'd feel pressure to think on what you're going to give out. I think I'd rather receive something from someone because they thought I'd like it, they thought of me, they saw it, they bought it. That is not something that should happen exclusively in Christmas. But if gifts aren't always in Christmas, what IS special about the date, then?<br>Say Christmas can be used as an excuse to get together with family, friends, loved ones. Having a specific day do get together is great. It is usually hard for my family, specially on my father's side, to be all together because everyone is doing their own thing, as they should, during most of the year. However, it makes it even harder, because everyone has at least two places to be, and we all tend to choose which one to go to on the 24th and go to the other place on the 25th. At least that's how it is done in my family. If my uncles don't agree on all going to my grandfather's place on the same date, then the whole thing of being all together doesn't work. It is easier to just choose an arbitrary day when we know we won't have a lot of plans around that date (like birthdays or stuff like that). Given the difficulty there already is to agree on a date, it would, in the worse case scenario, still be once a year, just like Christmas.<br>Others may say that is it also a day to be grateful for what we have, remember who is not here anymore, things that would actually be more related to Thanksgiving Day in the US that is, for some reason, celebrated by a lot of people around the world. But again, this is having a specific day for a certain something that can be done in any other day.<br>... You know? While writing this I realize that there are a few reasons on the participation in these days. The "excuses" to celebrate that I say can be done on any other day, those are the actual reasons on why holidays should exist nowadays. I guess we people are always just too busy with things going on in life, everybody is just doing the best they can on each day and we tend to be somewhat forgetful. We are too into out own things, as those things may demand, that we just forget to call people, think about them, etc. etc. So, I guess it's fine. I guess we can use these days to do all that we tend to not to during the rest of the year.<br>I do want to say that, if I was to organize something at my house, being all by myself and calling people to come, I would still understand if nobody came. Not that I'd be okay with them actively not wanting to be with me, but, as I said, people have other stuff. I know it is not always possible for plans to go as planned because things can change due to things that can be even out of our control. Just as happens to me, I do think about friends and remember the moments we have had together or imagine what I would like to do with them. Even if I can't go to someone's birthday, holiday meal, important event, I hope they know I still think of them. You, that are reading this, I am thinking of you. Not always will I send some kind of message or call or anything. But this doesn't mean I am not thinking of you. Quite the opposite. Perhaps some people can use or need these days more than others. I don't know, but you do. People be people, right?<br>However you are spending these days, I hope you spend them happily. Happy days, everyone. Be safe.]]></description><link>some-thoughts-on-december-holidays.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Some thoughts on December holidays.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 18:31:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why "People Be People"?]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>On 25th of December, 2024. At 21:45<br>Hi. I want to be ahead of any questions, although this is one I probably should have answered in the introduction to this blog. Why did I choose "People Be People" to name my blog? Mainly, this is just a small something that I like to say every now and then in certain situations. A few of those who know me irl might have heard me say or saw me write in a message "la gente es gente", which I'd translate to "people will be people".<br>Some years ago (don't ask me how many), I remember coming across this ad about how fathers shouldn't encourage "masculine behavior" on their boys; that they shouldn't justify their actions with "boys will be boys". The way I understood the phrase the first time I heard it was: "Oh, you know. This kind of behavior that they are showing is clearly not part of the set of learnings they've had on culture in this society, no. Rather, the way they act in inherent/intrinsic and the nature of the boys. There is nothing we can do to change them, but we can just accept the consequences of their actions while they are at this age because, well... boys will be boys".<br>The phrase itself affects society and makes boys think that it is okay to do what they do because boy have always been the same way and they never will change. But it is not only the belief that they will be the same, but the belief that they will be the same due to the lack of capacity to change. Worse yet, this tells all the boys that don't show this kind of behavior that they are weird, that they are not how boys are supposed to be and must change into the standard of what being a boy is.<br>Sure, to justify that boys can do whatever they want, they use this phrase. Something that I haven't heard yet, but wouldn't surprise, is "girls will be girls". In this context, the use of this phrase would be used also to say that a girl that can't do a certain something that is more related to what "men" or "boys" (can) do because it is not part of the standard of a girl, or that it is not in a girls nature to inherently be able to do this certain something. Similar case, but instead of an excuse for something that is done, it is an excuse for something that just can't be done. This also tells girls that they, by nature, can't do a certain something, while boys, by nature, just do those certain somethings.<br>By this point, I think it is somewhat worth mentioning that I, Shay, am non-binary (agender, maybe?) and I genuinely and honestly still don't get this gender thing and what exactly are those standards, how they are supposed to be or if there is anything fundamental about them. However, it is clear that limiting children by these means hinders their ability to learn or unlearn, or change how they are and who they are. This can be perfectly applied to adults as well, to "men" and "women", but I won't go any further in this to avoid repeating myself.<br>I have read on many people on the internet that say that there isn't any true nature about human beings. If this is true, then this must also be true for boys, girls, men, women, and people in general. Also, you might have heard or read a phrase that goes something like "the only thing that is constant in life is change", to say that everything is always changing and nothing really remains the same (please go listen to the Adventure Time song 'Time Adventure').<br>Combining this into an amalgam of thoughts, one thing that is part of human nature is precisely their ability to change. Not only to change, but the starting build is different for everyone. Everybody starts up in different conditions, different schemes, different cultures, different everything. Yet, nearly anyone can change these things about oneself and achieve quite similar results. Everyone is different, but we are also the same.<br>But... hold on... "boys will be boys" says that boys will never change. Is the blog "People Be People" because people will never change? Well, every single person, individually, can definitely change, but people as a whole? I think not. Let me elaborate. People are all capable of doing incredible things. The mere art of creation is something that amazes me every single time. So much people are so good at what they (love to) do. So many people, strangers, can be incredibly kind and lovely. So many people can have the most weirdest yet brilliant ideas. People can be so full of light. This also means that there can be people that act ethically/morally wrong, more than capable of committing crimes or any kind of harm to anyone. The whole of the characteristics and/or attributes of humans, I assure you, will never change.<br>Everyone is mostly capable of mostly everything. This is precisely why it is our actions that define us. We can and could do a lot of things, but we choose what we (want) to do among all of those possibilities. With this, there will always be people that do certain somethings, no matter what those somethings are (with some exceptions, of course). I truly believe humanity has been like this for a while, and, again, I don't think it will change anytime soon.<br>People will be people.<br>People Be People.]]></description><link>why-&quot;people-be-people&quot;/why-&quot;people-be-people&quot;.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Why &quot;People Be People&quot;?.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 03:45:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>