<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PBP]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>PBP</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:49:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:49:49 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[People Be People]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Hello, everyone!<br>I am Shay von Amyprost. If you are reading this it is because you have been wandering around my GitHub repositories, somehow discovered this link or I showed it to you in some way. In any case, be welcome to my wannabe blog!<br>Like many people, it wasn't since always that I question things about life in a society. This doesn't mean that this questioning began a little ago. Quite the opposite, I have been questioning for a while, but never really expressed anything, or only did to a very few and selected people. I want to start doing precisely that.<br>It is always better to have some people to talk to. In that line of thought, it would be better to have some sort of podcast. However, I do know myself enough to know that I like to rant (I tend to record and send relatively long audio messages). For this reason, I think this blog will be my way to go, for the time being.<br>If I have sent you the link to this blog, showed or presented it in a way that not everyone can see, feel free to contact me as you prefer, in case you want to discuss or talk about any topic that I write here. If you somehow managed to get this link somehow else, as described earlier, well... hold that thought! I will think of an "official" way of contacting me, so that I can have all of the comments specifically about this blog in one single place.<br>Without further ado, here is People Be People! :D]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 03:48:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>