<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Thesis II]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Thesis II</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:55:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:55:30 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Week 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Monday<br>
PMMA was cut. Molds for bottom layer and bottom layer holes (two separate pieces) were cut with the laser cutter.<br>
Molds were meant to be used to pour the PDMS and cure it in the shape of the holes to match the holes in the bottom layer.<br>Tuesday<br>
Prepared a petri dish with PDMS to then cut it into the shape of the holes and prior to curing in the Water Center, some of the PDMS was poured into the molds made from PDMS.<br>
After 2 hours, PDMS was not completely cured, and it was decided to leave it overnight. The temperature used was 130°C.<br>
PDMS mixture potentially not mixed well.<br>Wednesday<br>
PDMS was still not cured completely. The PDMS mixture was, indeed, not mixed properly. The PMMA mold layer was curved. PMMA cannot withstand those high temperatures for long times. I encountered Vahid in the lab. "Fully cured PDMS should not be cut too easily. You should do it again." This was done in the afternoon. Planned a new batch of PDMS for tomorrow.<br>
If PMMA molds are to be used, lower temperatures should be used. 60°C is recommended.<br>Thursday<br>
Made a new batch of PDMS in between my classes. It was thoroughly mixed (and vacuumed) and was left to cure in the Water Center at 130°C. No further attempt was made to use the molds. An attempt to cut the PDMS using the cutter plotter. PDMS layer was too think for the machine to cut it properly. "Fully cured PDMS should not be cut to easily". Fully cured PDMS is a little hard to cut.<br>
If a side goal of the project is to make the device reusable, the PDMS sample can't be too thin or it will not withstand high pressures in the air chamber. Thick PDMS pieces cannot be easily cut by the cutter plotter.<br>
If a thin piece of PDMS is to be used, the bottom of the device cannot be exposed. Bottom of the device should then be covered so that:<br>
1) PDMS piece stays in place during rotation (pressure)<br>
2) PDMS piece is capable of being removed with care and ease after the use of the device<br>
3) Cover of the bottom layer is such that there are no leakages anywhere on the circuit<br>
A clamp made from 3D printing resin could be made so that all the layers are maintained with enough force to prevent leakage but also easily removable to reuse the device with new PDMS samples<br>Friday<br>
There was no more curing agent to do another PDMS batch. The last batch of PDMS from Thursday was cut by hand using a knife and it was attempted to fit it into the holes of the molds. An easy leakage test was performed by placing small droplets of water on the hole with a piece of PDMS and a piece of paper was placed underneath. The paper piece got wet, meaning water could go through due to capillarity.<br>
A thin piece of PDMS should be used to prevent slowness caused by cutting thicker pieces<br>
It is necessary to find a way to cover the bottom layer that complies with the 3 statements from Thursday.<br>Saturday<br>
23:16<br>
Plans for Monday will include taping the PDMS piece to the bottom of the microfluidic platform using Pressure Sensitive Adhesive. The PDMS piece will come from the last batch of PDMS and will be placed under the already-made hole in the most recent chip.<br>
PSA has demonstrated to be really strong in terms of adhesion and could be a good way to apply pressure to the PDMS piece for it to stay in place. Since the PDMS piece will have a flat surface and no irregularities in shape, it should evenly seal the hole and prevent any leakages, also supported by the pressure onto the piece caused by the PSA tape.]]></description><link>Binnacle of Thesis II/Week 2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Binnacle of Thesis II/Week 2.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 18:25:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Monday<br>
12:27<br>
An attempt was made to seal the hole with the PDMS sample. As described in last Saturday's notes <a data-href="Week 2" href="Binnacle of Thesis II/Week 2.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Week 2</a>, a PDMS piece was cut with an area slightly bigger than the hole to cover. Something to note is that the hole in the microchannel has a square shape, but the hole made in the bottom acetate layer is rectangular, this was initially to expose some of the PSA glue and directly paste the substrate. This idea was discarded, as humidity and manipulation made the device non-reusable.<br>Looking at it another way, the glue and the acetate layers are in different levels. In the near micro scale, the adhesion was not perfectly leveled or aligned, which lead to leakages and further substrate detachment.<br>The same device was used for the idea mentioned above. In this scenario, instead of relying on adhesion or attachment caused by in-device materials (such as PSA layer), an external piece of PSA was used to keep the PDMS piece in place.<br>The device was placed upside down on a table, and the substrate was carefully placed on the hole. A small strip of PSA was placed on the substrate and device as follows: the center of the strip was pressed against the substrate; holding that pressure by hand, each side of the strip was pulled to maximize pressure and placed on the acetate layer. Only after both ends of the strip were pasted/placed, the pressure by hand was released.<br>Enough rotational speed (not tracked) was used to get the fluid to the other side of the substrate. Reciprocation was achieved successfully.<br>The issue that rose was that the substrate could not maintain the generated pressure for relatively long times or leakage occurs.<br>Regardless of the method used to attach (externally) the substrate onto the device, enough pressure maintained for enough time will cause leakage. An option to use this implementation is to redesign the device so that less pressure is necessary or to use the same design, but use high relaxation times (reverse flow time &gt;&gt; forward flow time) to have enough pressure relaxation to prevent leakages when the device accelerates again.]]></description><link>Binnacle of Thesis II/Week 3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Binnacle of Thesis II/Week 3.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 19:10:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mario's Binnacle/Bitacore/Log for Thesis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Hello, everyone.<br>This will be where I will be submitting and recording whatever I do everyday for my master's thesis project. More specifically, I will be recording the activities mainly for the experimental part (since the main thing of the theoretical part is code, so that is easier) unless stated otherwise: whenever I make relevant changes in the code (relevant means that it changes the result) I will describe them on the corresponding day.<br>I will be dividing this in weeks and in each week, it will be divided into the different days, including weekends in some situations, in case I just get an idea during those days. Otherwise, it will mainly be composed of Monday - Friday.<br>Ideas, thoughts and/or conclusions from activities will be in italics, as something to take into account for future related activities.<br>Any suggestions in the changes of format or arrangement are welcome.]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:55:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>