<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Thesis Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Thesis Log</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 17:57:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 17:57:41 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Week 17 (Nov 25 - Nov 29)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Throughout the week, different simulations and experiments were performed to obtain the right values for the mechanical properties (Young's Modulus and Poisson's ratio).<br>
First, a machine was used to obtain information in the form of a stress-strain diagram.<br>
The software of the machine provided the Young's Modulus. Different samples of different lengths were used.<br>Young's Modulus of CTR nitrile gloves
The Young's Modulus was estimated to be 6MPa  0.26MPa
<br>Due to unknown reasons, the machine did not provide the Poisson's ratio. Instead, simulations were run, changing the membrane radius and Poisson's ratio, and leaving the Young's Modulus as 6MPa.<br><img alt="v04.svg" src="lib/media/v04.svg" style="width: 600px; max-width: 100%;"><br>The figure shows results of the volume of liquid in the air chamber, considering a Poisson's ratio of 0.4. Upon comparing the results of the volume for these membrane radii (20mm, 22mm, and 24mm) considering different Poisson's ratios, where tests were performed, introducing 6mL, 8mL and 10mL into the source chamber and observing the behavior after the maximum speed was reached (600rpm), the ones that fitted best with the experimental obervations were those when the ratio of 0.4 was considered.<br>Poisson's ratio estimation
It was estimated that the Poisson's ratio has a value somewhere around 0.4
]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-17-(nov-25-nov-29).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 17 (Nov 25 - Nov 29).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:10:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/v04.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/v04.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 16 (Nov 19 - Nov 22)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>During this week, a tweaked version of the device was made.<br><img alt="Channel_depth_comp.png" src="lib/media/channel_depth_comp.png" style="width: 600px; max-width: 100%;"><br>In this figure, the depth of the channels is changed, from 40 microns as they originally were to 4mm as it is the width of the PMMA layer to use. The width of the channel was changed to be 0.5mm, as it is the width of the laser of a typical laser cutter.<br>The tweak mentioned earlier is to have the channels cut in the PMMA itself rather than on the PSA to have higher flow rate and reduce time needed for a reciprocation cycle.<br>A new brand of nitrile gloves was used. The Young's Modulus was tested to be 2MPa. However, for full accuracy of the code, the Poisson's ratio is also required.<br><img alt="v_comp.svg" src="lib/media/v_comp.svg"><br>The Poisson's ratio for nitrile has been estimated to be between 0.4 and 0.5, similar to other kinds of rubber. Here we can see the impact it has on the volume of fluid that enters the air chamber.<br>
A low Poisson's ratio is related to the maximum stress that can be held by the material before rupture. As this stress is related to the maximum expansion volume of the membrane, a low Poisson's ratio is favorable.<br>Study of different materials

<br>Study of Young's Modulus and Poisson's ratio of different materials could be a follow-up study on the best material for the membrane to use the smallest possible radius of it.

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-16-(nov-19-nov-22).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 16 (Nov 19 - Nov 22).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 04:59:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/channel_depth_comp.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/channel_depth_comp.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[LFA LOD improvement (secondary project)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Multiple attempts have been made in the past to use flow reciprocation as an increaser of residence time of fluid-air interface inside the LFA pieces (test line and control line). So far, the results have not been better than the standard LFA test.<br>Things to consider

<br>Diffusion can help extract the molecules and particles from the conjugate pad
<br>Some parts of the LFA kit may be removed and results would still be obtained
<br>Working mechanism and principles of LFA should be studied in order to determine how to increase their LOD with centrifugal microfluidic devices

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/lfa-lod-improvement-(secondary-project).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/LFA LOD improvement (secondary project).md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:19:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>PMMA was cut. Molds for bottom layer and bottom layer holes (two separate pieces) were cut with the laser cutter.<br>
Molds were meant to be used to pour the PDMS and cure it in the shape of the holes to match the holes in the bottom layer.<br><br>Prepared a petri dish with PDMS to then cut it into the shape of the holes and prior to curing in the Water Center, some of the PDMS was poured into the molds made from PDMS.<br>
After 2 hours, PDMS was not completely cured, and it was decided to leave it overnight. The temperature used was 130°C.<br>
PDMS mixture potentially not mixed well.<br><br>PDMS was still not cured completely. The PDMS mixture was, indeed, not mixed properly. The PMMA mold layer was curved. PMMA cannot withstand those high temperatures for long times. I encountered Vahid in the lab. "Fully cured PDMS should not be cut too easily. You should do it again." This was done in the afternoon. Planned a new batch of PDMS for tomorrow.<br>
If PMMA molds are to be used, lower temperatures should be used. 60°C is recommended.<br><br>Made a new batch of PDMS in between my classes. It was thoroughly mixed (and vacuumed) and was left to cure in the Water Center at 130°C. No further attempt was made to use the molds. An attempt to cut the PDMS using the cutter plotter. PDMS layer was too think for the machine to cut it properly. "Fully cured PDMS should not be cut to easily". Fully cured PDMS is a little hard to cut.<br>
If a side goal of the project is to make the device reusable, the PDMS sample can't be too thin or it will not withstand high pressures in the air chamber. Thick PDMS pieces cannot be easily cut by the cutter plotter.<br>
If a thin piece of PDMS is to be used, the bottom of the device cannot be exposed. Bottom of the device should then be covered so that:<br>
1) PDMS piece stays in place during rotation (pressure)<br>
2) PDMS piece is capable of being removed with care and ease after the use of the device<br>
3) Cover of the bottom layer is such that there are no leakages anywhere on the circuit<br>
A clamp made from 3D printing resin could be made so that all the layers are maintained with enough force to prevent leakage but also easily removable to reuse the device with new PDMS samples<br><br>There was no more curing agent to do another PDMS batch. The last batch of PDMS from Thursday was cut by hand using a blade and it was attempted to fit it into the holes of the molds. An easy leakage test was performed by placing small droplets of water on the hole with a piece of PDMS and a piece of paper was placed underneath. The paper piece got wet, meaning water could go through due to capillarity.<br>
A thin piece of PDMS should be used to prevent slowness caused by cutting thicker pieces<br>
It is necessary to find a way to cover the bottom layer that complies with the 3 statements from Thursday.<br><br>23:16<br>
Plans for Monday will include taping the PDMS piece to the bottom of the microfluidic platform using Pressure Sensitive Adhesive. The PDMS piece will come from the last batch of PDMS and will be placed under the already-made hole in the most recent chip.<br>
PSA has demonstrated to be really strong in terms of adhesion and could be a good way to apply pressure to the PDMS piece for it to stay in place. Since the PDMS piece will have a flat surface and no irregularities in shape, it should evenly seal the hole and prevent any leakages, also supported by the pressure onto the piece caused by the PSA tape.]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-2-(aug-12-aug-16).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16).md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 18:41:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 3 (Aug 19 - Aug 23)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>12:27<br>
An attempt was made to seal the hole with the PDMS sample. As described in last Saturday's notes <a data-href="Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16)" href="thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-2-(aug-12-aug-16).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16)</a>, a PDMS piece was cut with an area slightly bigger than the hole to cover. Something to note is that the hole in the microchannel has a square shape, but the hole made in the bottom acetate layer is rectangular, this was initially to expose some of the PSA glue and directly paste the substrate. This idea was discarded, as humidity and manipulation made the device non-reusable.<br>Looking at it another way, the glue and the acetate layers are in different levels. In the near micro scale, the adhesion was not perfectly leveled or aligned, which lead to leakages and further substrate detachment.<br>The same device was used for the idea mentioned above. In this scenario, instead of relying on adhesion or attachment caused by in-device materials (such as PSA layer), an external piece of PSA was used to keep the PDMS piece in place.<br>The device was placed upside down on a table, and the substrate was carefully placed on the hole. A small strip of PSA was placed on the substrate and device as follows: the center of the strip was pressed against the substrate; holding that pressure by hand, each side of the strip was pulled to maximize pressure and placed on the acetate layer. Only after both ends of the strip were pasted/placed, the pressure by hand was released.<br>Enough rotational speed (not tracked) was used to get the fluid to the other side of the substrate. Reciprocation was achieved successfully.<br>The issue that arose was that the substrate could not maintain the generated pressure for relatively long times or leakage occurs.<br>Regardless of the method used to attach (externally) the substrate onto the device, enough pressure maintained for enough time will cause leakage. An option to use this implementation is to redesign the device so that less pressure is necessary or to use the same design, but use high relaxation times (reverse flow time &gt;&gt; forward flow time) to have enough pressure relaxation to prevent leakages when the device accelerates again.<br>19:20<br>
Now that the skin cutter have arrived and the testing mold for the PDMS cylinder has been designed, tomorrow I will cut a couple of pieces of PDMS in the lab and will go to the Innovaction Gym to cut the mold in acrylic sheets on thicknesses of both 2mm and 3mm. As mentioned on Thursday's notes on <a data-href="Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16)" href="thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-2-(aug-12-aug-16).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Week 2 (Aug 12 - Aug 16)</a>, pressure accumulated could cause the PDMS to fall out of the device. However, if the piece is to thick, even though it will be more resistant to the pressure, it could cause the piece to be more difficult to be properly placed and removed, potentially damaging the surface. Since the current width of the channel is 4mm, ranges between 3.8mm and 4.1mm will be tested for the laser cutter.<br><br>12:28<br>
Went to CETEC to cut holes into a 2mm PMMA sheet. Since the last PDMS batch has a thickness of a little over 2mm, the 3mm sheet was not used, as there would be a space of 1mm inside the air chamber of the device where some of the liquid could get trapped. The overall design of the device was not changed. Only the bottom layer was redesigned and placed circular holes instead of square holes to accommodate the PDMS cylinders cut by the skin biopsy cutters (width of cutter chosen was of 4mm). The range of diameters mentioned on Monday did not work, as I didn't take into account the material removal by the laser cutter. The smallest hole (d=3.8mm) was scaled down with a factor of 0.8 (d=3.04mm), which was the ideal size to place the PDMS cylinders for them to be held in place but also not too difficult to place. Smaller sizes could lead to a more difficult placement and removal of the sample, potentially damaging the modified surface.<br>Upon filling the device and rotating, one of the channels presented leakage due to fabrication issues. The other channel was able to get the water a few mm beyond the PDMS piece. The rotation speed was maintained for a few seconds, until it began to present leakage as well, but this time it was leaking from the hole in which the PDMS piece was.<br>
Another issue arose when trying to remove the PDMS piece to change it for another one. The thickness of both the PMMA sheet and the PDMS are approximately the same, so tweezers were used to retrieve the piece. Pulling only from the bottom surface didn't suffice, as the PDMS is not rigid enough and it was cut by the tweezers. Instead, they were inserted into the air chamber from the sides of the hole, but with the pressure that had to be used, the top surface got deformed. This deformation could potentially damage a modified surface.<br>Regardless of the method used to hold the PDMS piece in place, enought pressure for enough time can lead to leakage from the intersections.<br>
Attempting another PDMS batch and pouring PDMS onto the holes to polymerize in the desired shape is recommended.<br><img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.56.00.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.56.00.jpeg"><br>
“WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 11.56.07.jpeg” could not be found.<br>
<img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 12.04.24.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-12.04.24.jpeg"><br>
<img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 12.05.10.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-12.05.10.jpeg"><br><br>The first idea was to directly paste a PDMS piece to an exposed portion of the PSA glue. However, a small piece would have a small area to attach to. Hence, the PDMS piece fell off easily, and pressure in the air chamber could cause leakages, weakening the attachment of the PDMS piece.<br>
<img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.42.08.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.42.08.jpeg"><br>Another idea was to use some sort of clamp to keep the PDMS in place. At first, a 3D printed clamp was used, but its design and weight made it very sensitive to rotational speeds and ended up falling off of the device. An alternative was to simply use a paper clip clamp (<a data-href="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.45.57.jpeg" href="binnacle-images/images/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.45.57.jpeg" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.45.57.jpeg</a>), but due to the geometry of it, the pressure distribution was uneven along the width of the channel. Despite the PDMS being held in place, one side of the PDMS was held with more force than the other. Because of this and the pressure in the air chamber, a leakage would occur.<br>
<img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.45.57.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.45.57.jpeg"><br>Then, as the different layers of the device were being held together by the Pressure Sensitive Adhesive and were difficult to separate, a piece of the PSA tape was used to keep the PDMS piecce in place. While it was possible to get to a rotational speed in which the water-air interface was beyond the PDMS piece, the pressure could not be maintained for more than some seconds (no more than, say, 15 seconds) without leakage. This would also happen if the speed was quickly decreased, but increased again. The reciprocation process could not be performed more than 4 times, with the maximum speed being held by just 5 seconds, before a leakage occured.<br>
<img alt="WhatsApp Image 2024-08-20 at 08.43.59.jpeg" src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.43.59.jpeg"><br>Lastly, the cylinder PDMS pieces in the cylinder PMMA holes, as described earlier, also lead to leakages.<br>*If putting the PDMS substrate outside of the device doesn't work no matter what is used to keep it in place, perhaps putting it inside the air chamber and designing the layers so that the device is "openable" might be the way to go. Perhaps a more rigid flat surface can be used if it is desired to have the substrate on the outside, but due to the PDMS compliance, leakage might still occur. A safer approach would be the mentioned earlier and have the PDMS on the inside, although this rises some things to consider in the design:<br>
<br>The main goal of microfluidics is the miniaturization and the possibility to lower the amount of sample required. If the PDMS samples to use have the same dimensions, a thicker device is necessary, but this would mean that more volume of liquid will be needed to cover a certain distance or fill up to a certain percentage.
<br>If it is desired to keep the volumes as low as possible, thinner pieces would be ideal, but harder to work with due to their flexibility, making them harder to handle and hold.
<br>Regardless of the decisions of design that are chosen, it is preferable that the PDMS sample is easily retrievable from the device to obtain proper results in modification reactions and lower the chances of damaging the surface to the minimum.
<br><br>After the attempts of attaching the PDMS substrate failed, I spent more time fixing the simulation codes. I can gladly say it has been a success. Here are the details of the main issues that were addressed:<br>
<br>Capillary pressure at constant angle was not working: although it is not mentioned explicitly in Ingmar Schwarz's doctoral thesis for capillary pressure, he does provides some pieces of code where some pressures under conditions of fully filled or fully emptied channels had to be 0. In cases there the flow rate and the time steps make the fill level higher or lower than 100% or 0% for filled and empty channels, the conditions establish that these pressure had to be 0 whenever the fill level was &gt;=100% or &lt;=0%. This way, it is ensured that they can work properly, and this is was the main fix for capillary pressure, as its value inside a channel must be zero whenever it is either fully filled or completely empty.
<br>Pressure difference equations inside chambers: in Ingmar Schwarz's doctoral thesis, in section 2, he describes how Simscape works, and provides simple codes for simple microfluidic components to show how they connect in the graphic interface and interact. In this section, he provides simple code for a source of liquid and a radial channel, in which he establishes the pressure difference inside the channel to be equal to the viscous pressure caused by the fluid resistance minus the centrifugal pressure. A more detailed version of this equation is not found anywhere else in the thesis, but in the article that resulted from it. In that paper, the pressure difference in a radial channel is denoted as  . With the thinking that pcent and p_cap are pressures associated to forces that drive the fluid in the forward direction, and p_visc and p_iner are pressures associated to forces that oppose to the movement of the fluid, this equation was used as a base for all the other components with their respective predominant pressures. For the vented chamber we have that $\Delta p + p{cent} + p{Euler} = 0$ , as there are no dominant forces that oppose to the fluid exiting the chamber. We could say that the same pressures that apply for a channel would apply for chambers, but as Ingmar Scharz says in his thesis, these forces are negligible in chambers. With this, we have that for the pneumatic chamber $\Delta p + p{cent} + p{Euler} = p{pneum}$ ,  and for the isoradial channel we have that  . With these equations, the calculation of the flow rate and pressure are adequate.
<br>Reverse flow: in Ingmar Schwarz codes for the library, there is no proper implementation of a reverse flow, as adding more than one connection per port tempered with the signals going into the components. To achieve flow reciprocation in the pneumatic chamber due to the pneumatic pressure, new ports where added.
<br>Isoradial orientation: Ingmar Schwarz implemented a single equation for the Euler pressure. This would for one orientation, as the Euler force vector also depends on the orientation vector of the channel. For this reason, a parameter  was added int he set of modifiable parameters for the isoradial channel, with values of 1 and -1, to multiply the Euler pressure value depending on the orientation of the channel.
<br>The complete library is now available at <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/PastaG1903/C_uF_lumped_MATLAB" target="_blank">https://github.com/PastaG1903/C_uF_lumped_MATLAB</a><br><br>There could be a way to work with thin pieces of PDMS if the reactions are carried on using Petri dishes instead of beakers, since they have a wider area. This makes it easier to retrieve these pieces as opposed to when beakers are used (with thin pieces). Furthermore, if a clamp is made with flexible resin perimeter-wide, it is possible that the layers can be sandwiched in a fashion that allows the user to disassemble the device to retrieve the sample without harming it. It would be optimal to work, at least, with 1mm acrylic sheets rather than 0.5mm. Depending on the final design, it might be necessary to use even 2mm of thickness, but the issue of how much volume is required can be simply fixed by placing the sample closer to the air chamber inlet.  ]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-3-(aug-19-aug-23).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 3 (Aug 19 - Aug 23).md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 02:58:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.56.00.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/whatsapp-image-2024-08-20-at-08.56.00.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 4 (Aug 26 - Aug 30)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The next tasks regarding or related to the simulation are:<br>
<br>Change the circuit and parameters in the simulation to match the current design
<br>Perform a literature review on deformation of membrane with respect to pressure
<br>Perform experiments to obtain a graph of deformation vs pressure of the current membrane
<br><br>Attempt to use even smaller sizes of hole in the PMMA. As there is no more curing agent to make a new batch of PDMS, the batch of 2mm thickness will still be used. A 1mm thickness sheet of PMMA might be desirable to have a 1mm portion of the substrate outside the device. This would allow easier retrieval of the substrate. As stated on <a data-href="Week 3 (Aug 19 - Aug 23)" href="thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-3-(aug-19-aug-23).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Week 3 (Aug 19 - Aug 23)</a>, on Tuesday, the smallest hole used for the 2mm thickness PMMA sheet was of 3.8mm and scaled down with a factor of 0.8, giving a hole of approximately 3.04mm in diameter. The same size (3.8mm) will be tested on the 1mm thick sheet and then scaled down. The two initial tests would be with holes of 3.8 and 3.04mm and test intermidiate values if needed. Else, will continue on scaling down.<br>
It is important that the substrate is not very difficult to put in the hole. Otherwise, the surface modification can be severely damaged due to the contact with the sheet in the process of inserting the substrate.<br>
It would be important to, once able to reciprocate without leakage, repeat the chemical reactions, to make sure the substrate actually stays as intact as possible. Two pieces can be used: one for control which will be not put in the device and will undergo FTIR analysis after reactions and another one that will be analyzed after putting in and then pulling out the substrate. This is to compare how much of the modification is maintained.  <br><br>The simulation parameters of the vented and pneumatic chamber have been changed to allow input of width and depth, instead of calculating them from the total volume capacity and the length. The parameters of the different components were changed to match those of the experimental device. These are as follows:<br>
<br>Vented chamber:

<br>Azimuthal position of outlet: 0 (centered)
<br>Initial fill level: 1 
<br>Depth: 540 m
<br>Width: 15mm
<br>Length: 15mm
<br>Distance to center: 12.5mm


<br>Radial channel:

<br>Width: 2mm
<br>Depth: 40 m
<br>Inlet radial distance: 27.5mm
<br>Outlet radial distance: 57.5mm
<br>Initial fill level: 0
<br>Contact angle for p_cap: pi/4


<br>Isoradial channel:

<br>Width: 2mm
<br>Depth: 40 m
<br>Length: 21.5mm
<br>Radius: 55.7mm
<br>Initial fill level: 0
<br>Contact angle for p_cap: pi/4
<br>Direction: -1 (flow from inlet is clockwise)


<br>Pneumatic chamber:

<br>Azimuthal position of inlet: 0 (centered)
<br>Initial fill level: 0
<br>Depth: 540 m
<br>Width: 4mm
<br>Length: 36mm
<br>Distance to center: 20.5mm


<br><br>A new testing  design was made for the circular cutters, with circles ranging from 2.8mm and 3.1mm in diameter. Despite the last test results discarded 3.1mm diameter, these new cuts will be made on a 1mm thickness sheet. Perhaps it is worth trying.<br>
Equations for the change in the membrane were found. So luckily, after experiments today, it will be possible to implement this membrane in the simulation.<br>
The minimum size in the design for the PDMS pieces was established at 2.8mm for the fitting of the 4mm diameter pieces.<br>
Images of the balloon inflation were taken and will be thereafter analyzed.<br><br>The bulge height was estimated from the images taken on Thursday.<br>
For the 5000Pa, it is 2.29mm  0.02mm.<br>
For the 4000Pa, it is 1.69mm  0.01mm.<br>
For the 3000Pa, it is 1.235mm  0.15mm.<br>
For the 2000Pa, it is 0.776mm  0.007mm.<br>For the PMMA pieces, a set of trial-and-error experiments should be done to bake the laser cuts as clean as possible<br>As found in one paper, there is an equation that relates the bulge height of the inflated membrane with the pressure accumulated in the chamber. After regression and data analysis to find the right values and coefficients for said equation, the results were not very conclusive. More pictures with pressures ranging from 60mbar to 100mbar are required for a more complete analysis.]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-4-(aug-26-aug-30).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 4 (Aug 26 - Aug 30).md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:23:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 5 (Sep 2 - Sep 6)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Today, further cutting tests will be performed to get the bottom layer holes to be as flat as possible, with as minimum residue of melted material as possible. <br><br>The equation found relating the pressure inside the chamber and the bulge height of the circular latex membrane was:<br>
p = C M t h  a + C  t h a<br>
The expression for the current design is:<br>
p =  (-1.095)(2.817E10)h + 4(0.7813)(835170.18658)h<br>The next activities to perform as per the weekly meeting today are the following:<br>
<br>DONE Finish the code by implementing the change in volume in the pneumatic chamber due to the inflation of the membrane.

<br>DONE Relate the bulge height with the volume change.
<br>DONE Add the volume change to the volume in the pneumatic chamber.


<br>Finalize substrate-placing in the device with no leakages.

<br>DONE Find a combination of speed and power of the laser cutter to prevent having melted material on the substrate hole.
<br>Make a device to test for leakages.


<br>DONE Use the finalized version of the code to minimize the amount of sample needed in the device.

<br>DONE Play with geometry parameters and velocity profiles to achieve the same pressures/fluid distance with as less fluid as possible.


<br>Build a prototype of the final design with the substrate (with the minimized volume).

<br>Use the simulation results to design and build a device, adding into it the minimal sample volume, and check if results are consistent with simulation.


<br>Perform tests on LFA with the Prostate Specific Antigen.

<br>Test antigen, sample pad, test line and control line in a beaker under agitation to see if there is any improvement with respect to standard LFA.
<br>Build a device with the components of LFA in the device and see if there is any improvement with respect to standard LFA and agitation.


<br><br>In the equation described on Monday, we can have h = , where a is the radius of the membrane,  to get the volume enclosed below the spherical cap to use it with the pneumatic pressure, since a change in volume will make the pneumatic pressure to increase much slower and the fluid can move farther into the chamber.<br><br>After further examination of the approximation on the equation mentioned on Monday, at higher pressures, the equation caused the bulge height to decrease, which makes no physical sense. Therefore, another approximation was used using other constants that will be further explained.<br>
Instead of the negative number, (8/3)0.8 was used, and instead of 83..., which is meant to be the initial stress in the membrane, 620000Pa was used. This approximation did not quite fit the real values, but it was the only approximation with physical sense that got closer to the experimental values.<br>
It is important to note that it is possible that more measurements or more pictures could have been necessary to obtain the correct experimental values.<br>
Another thing which is more relevant and equally possible is the paralax error introduced in the measurements, which was not taken into account the first time an approximation was attempted.<br><br>Task 1 from Monday is complete.<br>
Subtask 2.1 from Monday is complete. Subtask 2.2 will be performed on Monday on Week 6.<br><br>An easy way to ensure that the substrate can be fully covered with liquid is by placing it as close to the inlet of the pneumatic chamber as possible. According to the equation used, one thing that helps achieve greater distances with less rotational speed is by ensuring that the membrane has the least initial stress as possible, which is a parameter that will be taken into account when fabricating.<br>
Nonetheless, elongating the chamber so there is more air to compress, reduces the pneumatic pressure at a specific rotational speed, allowing more distance covered at lower speeds. According to the simulation's results, this is a good way to go. Around a centimeter can be easily reached at 10Hz, with a volume of sample less than 30 microliters.<br><img alt="Pasted image 20240908122413.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240908122413.png" style="width: 590px; max-width: 100%;">]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-5-(sep-2-sep-6).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 5 (Sep 2 - Sep 6).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:41:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240908122413.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240908122413.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 6 (Sep 9 - Sep 13)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>As per the meeting and the list of activities established from last week, this is the updated version of said list:<br>
<br>Fabricate the device and test for leakages.
<br>If no leakage is present, test if modification stays in reusable process.

<br>Coat 2 pieces of PDMS, use one for control.
<br>Test one in FTIR to see if the coat is present.
<br>In a sealed prototype, place the PDMS substrate onto the bottom layer of the device.
<br>Remove the substrate and use FTIR to see if coating is still present.


<br>Do some tests on LFA kits to see if any kind of movement contributes to the LOD or color in the control line.
<br><br>Melted material minimized, but not removed
There had been leakage in the microchannels.<br>
Upon further inspection, the previous devices also presented these leakages attributed to fabrication issues.<br>
Melted material rises the PSA, causing improper adhesion and leakages.
<br>Use acetate as bottom layer
If melted material is an issue, acetate could be used as the bottom layer.<br>
If in the thicker PMMA layer there is leakage in the substrate holes, it should start on the inner surface.<br>
If there is leakage in those holes using the acetate layer, it would be the same with the PMMA.
<br><br>The acetate layer as bottom layer was a good alternative. The main issue was that the portion of PDMS inside the pneumatic chamber caused a narrowing that increased the capillary forces on the substrate. This caused that portion of the chamber to be constantly wet, despite the rest of re fluid recession into the source chamber.<br>Improvements for thicker bottom layer usage
Firstly, if melted material is a problem on the edges of the device, the bottom layer can be slightly larger to prevent leakages on microchannels due to anisotropies from the melted material.<br>
Molds can be used to make the substrate in a better shape for better fitting inside the holes of the bottom layer.
<br>Next steps for device finalization

<br>Design molds for an easy retrieval of the substrates after curing.
<br>Make PDMS substrates and re-test fittin on bottom layer holes.
<br>Fabricate a new device and check for leakages, ensuring that the capturing surface is at the same level as the bottom layer surface.

<br><br>For the design of the molds, the plan is to make them as 5 simple cylinders. When cutting the PDMS with the skin cutters, the cut piece got stuck in the inside of the cutter. For easy retrieval of the pieces from the molds, a set of covers will be printed as well to act as the bottom and top surfaces where the pieces will be.<br>
The cylinders will have a height of 5mm and a wall thickness of 1mm. A tolerance of 0.1mm diameter will be used for the covers.<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240914132349.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240914132349.png"><br>
Inner radius: 2mm<br>
Outer radius: 3mm<br>
Height: 5mm<br>
<img alt="Pasted image 20240914132625.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240914132625.png"><br>
Inner radius: 3.05mm<br>
Outer radius: 4mm<br>
Height of hollow space: 2mm<br>
Height of cylinder cap: 2mm<br>Update of activities

<br>Design molds for an easy retrieval of the substrates after curing.
<br>Make PDMS substrates and re-test fittin on bottom layer holes.
<br>Fabricate a new device and check for leakages, ensuring that the capturing surface is at the same level as the bottom layer surface.

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-6-(sep-9-sep-13).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 6 (Sep 9 - Sep 13).md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 19:52:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240914132349.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240914132349.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 7 (Sep 17 - Sep 20)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Monday was holiday.<br>
The main activities for this week are presented bellow.<br>Week 7 Activities

<br>Print several molds for PDMS substrates (around 20 should suffice).
<br>Test cured resin for heating resistance.
<br>If heating tests are positive, cure PDMS substrates under heat. Else, cure at room temperature.
<br>Test fitting of substrates in bottom acrylic layer
<br>Test device for leakages with new substrates. Substrates should be at surface-level of acrylic.

<br>Important notes

<br>PDMS molds have an approximate volume of 60uL, grouped in sets of 5. Leading to the need of 4 sets of 5 molds to achieve a volume higher than 1mL.
<br>The higher the temperature, the faster the PDMS polymerizes. If heating tests of the resin are negative, it will have a delay of one day for the rest of activites.
<br>For the internal geometry of the pneumatic chamber to not change, the substrate has to be at the same level as the internal face of the acrylic sheet. Having it this way is crucial to not let fluid get stuck in a well-like structure due to the substrate being bellow that level.

<br><br>The molds and caps for the PDMS where originally designed using FreeCAD software. Upon exporting the files to STL, the molds and caps were separated into individual pieces, which might actually help have a better control over the amount of substrates available and produced.]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-7-(sep-17-sep-20).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 7 (Sep 17 - Sep 20).md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 22:54:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 8 (Sep 23 - Sep 27)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>As per described on <a data-href="Week 7 (Sep 17 - Sep 20)" href="thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-7-(sep-17-sep-20).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Week 7 (Sep 17 - Sep 20)</a> Tuesday's list of activities, the PDMS was finally put into some molds and left to cure wrapped in aluminum foil at 70°C overnight. Only 5 molds were filled to test for shape and ease of retrieval. They will be retrieved on Tuesday morning. An updated version of the activities list is shown below.<br>Activities for the week

<br>Retrieve and check PDMS cylinders
<br>Fill the rest of the molds and cure PDMS
<br>Cut PMMA if cylinders don't fit the current bottom layers
<br>Fabricate new device and test for fitting and leakages

<br>Furthermore, if there is enough time throughout the week, some additional yet important tasks could be done.<br>Additional tasks

<br>Perform chemical modifications on PDMS cylinder substrates (triplicates yet again)
<br>Check modification retainence on the surface before and after insertion in bottom layer

<br><br>New bottom layers were cut and PDMS molds were filled and left to cure overnight. It is expected that the molds will help the PDMS maintain a good shape for the substrate to completely seal the air chamber and prevent any leakages.<br><br>The PDMS substrates were retrieved. Upon 3 tests, the best way to remove them is to separate the piece from the walls of the cylinder mold using pointy tweezers. Then, when most of it has separated, push the substrate out.<br>
The device was successfully fabricated. The PDMS substrate was slightly bigger than the hole, so there is some effort required to fit it inside the device. However, it can be done in a way that most of the surface remains untouched during the process, which will be further confirmed with modification experiments.<br>
First, an issue must be addressed: the thickness of the middle layer, which gives height to the middle layer, is very small. With the insertion of the PDMS substrate, the surface ends up touching the internal face of the top layer, which can potentially damage the surface modification.<br>Successes

<br>Fabricated PDMS cylinders that fit into the holes
<br>No leakages were found in the device
<br>Reciprocation was achieved

<br>Issues found

<br>Due to the insertion procedure of the PDMS substrate, surface touches the top layer. Modifications might get damaged

<br>Solution of issues

<br>Middle layer of 1mm and holes on bottom layer closer to entrance can lead to better performance with the same sample volume

<br>Flow reciprocation was achieved. To test for both leakages and reciprocation, the device was spun. If no sign of leakage was perceptible, the device was stopped and the recession of the fluid was observed.<br>
<img alt="20240925_111547.jpg" src="lib/media/20240925_111547.jpg" style="width: 450px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
<img alt="20240925_111712.jpg" src="lib/media/20240925_111712.jpg" style="width: 450px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br>Alternative solution
A different approach to avoid increasing the size of the air chamber can be changing the method of insertion of PDMS

<br>PDMS will be inserted by twisting and pushing instead of just pushing
<br>This method might make the insertion process more controllable, allowing for a better leveling of the modified surface.

<br>Success
It is possible to introduce and control the PDMS cylinder substrate by rotating it while pressing.
<br>Non-uniform placement

<br>Although it is possible to fit the PDMS cylinder substrates into the bottom layer holes, they are a lot wider, considering the scale of operation, than the holes, making it difficult to place it as leveled as possible.
<br>Fluid can go above the PDMS piece, but due to improper alignment and leveling, the pressure can lead to eventual leakage after some reciprocation cycles.

<br>Substrate damaging

<br>After a few attempts of fitting a substrate, the edges and sides of the cylinder get damaged due to the size difference
<br>Experiments of chemical modifications have demonstrated that, upon cleaning, the substrate can be modified again, but it gets difficult to reuse if substrate gets damaged.

<br>Decrease internal size of PDMS molds

<br>Measurements will be taken to reduce the size of PDMS molds to make thinner cylinders to make it easier to place, but with enough tolerance to make the device leakage-free

<br>Increase size of PMMA hole

<br>Alternatively, a knife can be used to increase the size of the already existing holes. This is to avoid wasting material and use the already cut pieces

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-8-(sep-23-sep-27).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 8 (Sep 23 - Sep 27).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 22:42:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/20240925_111547.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/20240925_111547.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 9 (Sep 30 - Oct 4)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>It was chosen to create new molds with less diameter for them to fit better into the PMMA holes. Tests of fitting and chemical reactions will be done on Wednesday for both types of substrates that have been made.<br>Activities for the week
Test fitting of new substrates onto the PMMA bottom layer holes<br>
Test chemical reactions and analyze before and after placement
<br><br>New PDMS not cured
PDMS was not mixed well and therefore not cured.<br>
Old PDMS molds should be tested before new molds are made necessary.
<br>Test chemical reactions on old PDMS cylinder substrates
The chemical reactions should be tested on the cylinders.<br>
One cylinder will serve as control. After that, 3 cylinders will be introduced into the device and then analyzed for the PAMAM attachment with FTIR.
<br>Control and first instance tested
The modification was retained even after extracting the PDMS cylinder from the device.
<br><img alt="PAMAM_comp_cyl.png" src="lib/media/pamam_comp_cyl.png"><br>Complete triplicates
It is necessary to perform the experiment with 3 cylinders to ensure the correct performance of the modification and if it is retained after inserting them into the device.
]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-9-(sep-30-oct-4).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 9 (Sep 30 - Oct 4).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:45:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pamam_comp_cyl.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pamam_comp_cyl.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 10 (Oct 7 - Oct 11)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A new device was designed to ensure that all of the sample to use passed by the substrate. This allows to use even less amount of sample volume by not needing to consider the accumulated unused volume that remains inside the microchannels.<br>
The main idea is to fabricate it in such a way that all of the sample returns to the source chamber in the microfluidic circuit.<br>
<img alt="Week 10 (Oct 7 - Oct 11)-20241012231905083.webp" src="lib/media/week-10-(oct-7-oct-11)-20241012231905083.webp" style="width: 250px; max-width: 100%;"><img alt="Week 10 (Oct 7 - Oct 11)-20241012232301590.webp" src="lib/media/week-10-(oct-7-oct-11)-20241012232301590.webp" style="width: 250px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
The first figure is the Pressure Sensitive Adhesive layer for the overall circuit. The second figure is the middle PMMA layer. The left circle is the source chamber, while the right one is the pneumatic chamber. In the PMMA design, the slot in the left half, below the source chamber, is meant to be the space for the PDMS substrate.<br>
As the microfluidic channels exhibit strong capillary forces compared to other components, like the chambers. This, along with the dimensions of the microchannels, makes the air volume that gets to the pneumatic chamber negligible. To ensure that there is an initial pressure increase to fully reciprocate all of the fluid, the space dedicated for the PDMS substrate has the same height as the chambers, to ensure that the air inside is transported to the pneumatic chamber as fluid starts filling that space.]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-10-(oct-7-oct-11).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 10 (Oct 7 - Oct 11).md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 05:33:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/week-10-(oct-7-oct-11)-20241012231905083.webp" length="0" type="image/webp"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/week-10-(oct-7-oct-11)-20241012231905083.webp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 11 (Oct 14 - Oct 18)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Today, there was a meeting with Dr. Xudong, professor in charge of the project on the end of University of Ottawa. As per the standards and regulations of bacterial contamination of water dictate, it is necessary that the device is able to detect bacteria in very low concentrations.<br>
For this matter, the redesign of the device will involve the usage of, at least, 10mL of sample volume. This means that, mainly, the source and pneumatic chambers will have to be redesigned to accommodate this volume.<br>
Ideally, the thickness of the middle layer should be kept at 0.5mm. This allows easy fabrication. Thicker pieces, considering that the bottom layer already has a thickness of 2mm, could potentially lead to improper adhesion of the Pressure Sensitive Adhesive.<br>
For this reason, only the rest of the dimensions of the source and pneumatic chambers will be changed.<br><br>After a little bit of thought and consideration of the dimensions of the materials available, the redesign to accommodate 10mL in the device's chambers was done.<br>
<img alt="Week 11 (Oct 14 - Oct 18)-20241016163051655.webp" src="lib/media/week-11-(oct-14-oct-18)-20241016163051655.webp" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br>The previous design, as stated before, was meant to hold  10mL in the source chamber and  20mL in the air chamber of total volume. The air chamber was designed this way to have some amount of air to be able to achieve reciprocation without disrupting much the unions between the materials.<br>
<img alt="20241017_121429.jpg" src="lib/media/20241017_121429.jpg" style="width: 400px; max-width: 100%;"><br><img alt="20241017_121453.jpg" src="lib/media/20241017_121453.jpg" style="width: 400px; max-width: 100%;"><br>As it can be seen, the middle PMMA layer, containing the chambers and the slot for the PDMS substrate, can be easily filled in the latter slot. This could primarily be due to the substrate slot having the same width as the microfluidic channel.<br>
An alternative could be to reduce the width of the channels. However, during rotation, the fluid will naturally enter this chamber due to the geometry of the circuit. In any case, it will matter the most that reciprocation is possible.<br><img alt="20241017_121520.jpg" src="lib/media/20241017_121520.jpg" style="width: 400px; max-width: 100%;"><br>In this previous picture, it can be seen that that there are some lines, which indicate leakage into the space between the layers of the design. This is very likely to be caused by the lack of sufficient adhesion with the Pressure Sensitive Adhesive. This could be addressed by two ways.<br>
1) To use a pressing machine or laminator to press all the layers together. It is important to note that good enough adhesion of very thick layers could be very difficult.<br>
2) A more practical way would be to simply change the thickness of the bottom layer from 2mm to 0.5mm.<br>The reason why 2mm was chosen as the thickness of the bottom layer with the substrate hole was due to the height of the channel. A small height can make it very difficult to place the substrate when this placement can be done with relative ease. It would be possible to "over-insert" the substrate and cause, by accident, the modified surface to touch the internal roof of the channel. This interaction would cause a significant loss of the modification. A thicker piece would cause more friction with the substrate, allowing more control when inserting it.<br>Now that the middle PMMA layer being of 2-3 mm thickness, the height of the substrate slot allows for more freedom in the placement of the substrate with sufficient control. If no leakage is present, it could be possible to use this thinner layer and fabricate as usual without the need of another machine or equipment. <br>Next activities

<br>Redesign microchannels and reduce the width
<br>Use the 0.5mm thickness layer as the bottom layer and re attempt fabrication
<br>Test yet another device for leakages around the substrate hole

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-11-(oct-14-oct-18).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 11 (Oct 14 - Oct 18).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 23:09:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/week-11-(oct-14-oct-18)-20241016163051655.webp" length="0" type="image/webp"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/week-11-(oct-14-oct-18)-20241016163051655.webp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 12 (Oct 21 - Oct 25)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>As proposed last week, it would be beneficial to decrease the width of the channel where the PDMS substrate is. However, this would lead to remake the substrates. For that reason, it was simply kept as it was.<br>
Another attempt to fabricate the device was made, with the bottom layer still being 2mm thick.<br><img alt="20241021_134931.jpg" src="lib/media/20241021_134931.jpg" style="width: 500px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Device fabrication not possible with thick layers
Due to the thickness of the layers, it is not possible to press them in such a way that they remain adhered through the Pressure Sensitive Adhesive. Therefore, leakage is very likely to happen
<br>Next steps

<br>Fabricate a new device with a new 0.5mm thickness bottom layer with the hole for the PDMS substrate

<br><br>As per the suggestion of the supervisor, the bottom layer of the new device was made from an acetate sheet instead of using 0.5mm thickness PMMA.<br>
All the other dimensions were kept the same as last week's device.<br><img alt="20241022_132214.jpg" src="lib/media/20241022_132214.jpg" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Resolved issues

<br>It was possible to fabricate the device without leakage in the PSA

<br>New issues

<br>Due to the very small thickness of the acetate sheets, leakage is present around the PDMS substrate as it was in previous cases
<br>Wobbling of the device during rotation causes instability and prevents tests to be done properly.

<br>New assignments

<br>Modify the overall device design to include a counterweight to balance out the device
<br>Modify the overall design to incorporate properly the substrate without leakages

<br><br>Some rings were designed to be placed around the hole to act in a similar manner as the thick 2mm layer that was previously being used.<br>
Initially, it didn't seem to leak, but the wobbling of the device lead to inconclusive results.<br>Prevent wobbling

<br>Similar weight on the opposite side of the circuit to act as counterweight

<br><br>Implement a single circuit in the whole disc

<br>The design of the device was made such that 2 circuits could be incorporated in a single disk
<br>It should be possible to make the circuit (chambers) in the whole disk to reduce its diameter and use itself as counterweight
<br>This would lead to have one circuit per disk

<br>Design is not possible with 2mm thick acrylic

<br>Considering the width of PSA is 15cm, it is not possible to design the device to have a single circuit in one disk with any degree of margin in between the chambers

<br>Design possible with middle layer of 3mm

<br>Source Chamber: r of 15mm and R of 49mm. Angle of 176°, A=3342.096mm
<br>Air Chamber: r of 49mm and R of 68mm. Angle of 174°, A=3375.48422mm

<br><img alt="Week 12 (Oct 21 - Oct 25)-20241028085405122.webp" src="lib/media/week-12-(oct-21-oct-25)-20241028085405122.webp">]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-12-(oct-21-oct-25).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 12 (Oct 21 - Oct 25).md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 14:54:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/20241021_134931.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/20241021_134931.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 13 (Oct 28 - Nov 1)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Perks of one circuit in one CD

<br>Length restriction due to PSA dimensions causes cuts in PMMA layer to be very close to each other
<br>During fabrication, the small amounts of melted material in adjacent chambers could cause water to leak
<br>The closeness of the chambers also makes for a troublesome fabrication

<br>The PSA layers incorporation onto the PMMA middle layer was made as fabrication steps, during which some issues were encountered as mentioned above.<br>
Yet another redesign will be made to incorporate one circuit in only one half of the disc.<br>Design possible with 2mm PMMA layer

<br>Source chamber: 82°, (R=85, r=15), Area=5009.09495mm^2
<br>Air chamber: 82°, (R=120, r=85), Area=5134.322327mm^2

<br><br>Friday's design, one circuit in CD, works

<br>The idea of having the circuit cover the entire CD was to have the center of mass at the rotation axis
<br>Despite the perks mentioned on Monday, no water leakages were present
<br>Acetate bottom layer was used, and no leakage around the substrate area were present
<br>Flow reciprocation is possible

<br><img alt="20241029_181430.jpg" src="lib/media/20241029_181430.jpg" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"> Complete device as per the design established on Friday, <a data-href="Week 12 (Oct 21 - Oct 25)" href="thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-12-(oct-21-oct-25).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Week 12 (Oct 21 - Oct 25)</a><br><img alt="20241029_131922.jpg" src="lib/media/20241029_131922.jpg" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
<img alt="20241029_131945.jpg" src="lib/media/20241029_131945.jpg" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"> Water in the source chamber (bottom right) a few seconds after removing from motor<br><img alt="20241029_132008.jpg" src="lib/media/20241029_132008.jpg" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"> Water in the source chamber (bottom right) three minutes after rotation<br>Design improvement

<br>Change the membrane diameter to decrease the reciprocation time

<br><br>The code was updated for the new design.<br>
The rest of the day was dedicated to other academic activities.<br><br>There was the intention to make some tests changing the membrane size to see the speed of the reciprocation.<br>
During fabrication, there were some issues, but at the first try, there was no problem.<br>Fabrication issue

<br>During rotation, the PSA near the fabrication defect starts to come apart. When pressure is applied, it eventually separates and water starts leaking.

<br>Tweak design

<br>It is possible to extend the air chamber to avoid further defects and water flow directly between the chambers (which happened during rotation)

<br><br>After the meeting, key activities to do were defined.<br>Experimental activities
Finalize the device

<br>Reshape (round) the corners of the design to minimize leakage or unwanted fluid transport
<br>Find optimal membrane size for reciprocation based on receding speed

<br>Theoretical (simulation) activities
Finalize code for new design

<br>Update the code, implementing the necessary changes for the new geometries
<br>Validate simulation results with experiments
<br>Extract diagrams/plots/graphs from the resulting data using variations in parameters

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-13-(oct-28-nov-1).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 13 (Oct 28 - Nov 1).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:54:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/20241029_181430.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/20241029_181430.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 14 (Nov 4 - Nov 8)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Throughout the week, the different points for improving the microfluidic device were addressed, mainly the rounding of corners and membrane size.<br>Bypass still occurs in round corners

<br>At a certain pressure, PSA from between the source/inlet and air chambers can detach, creating a small channel from which bypass can occur, regardless of the shape.
<br>Closeness of chambers is responsible for the threshold pressure for this detachment.

<br>Due to the bypass, it was noticeable that the PDMS substrate was not getting wet.<br>If bypass, then no reciprocation

<br>The bypass channel causes the pressure inside the air chamber to be released by transmitting the air displaced by water.
<br>Due to air transport instead of water/fluid transport, there cannot be any reciprocation.

<br>Optimization for low velocities

<br>Using the current version of the simulation, an estimate can be done of the ideal range of membrane radius for an adequate flow rate at lower angular speeds.
<br>With this, use of lower velocities can be ensured to lower the risk of bypass in the same design.

<br><br>As per the meeting today with the supervisor, the design of the device will change. Instead of using 3mm sheets for the middle layer, there will be designs for 4mm and 5mm to reduce dimensions of the chambers of the circuit, with the goal of still having a full disc to act as a balanced weight.<br>New dimensions for 4mm thickness

<br>Source chamber: 160° as aperture angle. R=45. r = 15.
<br>Air chamber: 160° as aperture angle. r = 45. R = 62.

<br>New dimensions for 5mm thickness

<br>Source chamber: 128° as aperture angle. r = 15. R = 45.
<br>Air chamber: 128° as aperture angle. r = 45. R = 62.

]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-14-(nov-4-nov-8).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 14 (Nov 4 - Nov 8).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week 15 (Nov 11 - Nov 15)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Fabrication of 4mm design prototype

<br>A prototype for the 4mm design, using a 2mm PMMA sheet, was fabricated
<br>Increased space between the chambers prevented internal leakages of bypass of the PDMS substrate
<br>Reciprocation was possible. A membrane with a diameter of 16mm was used

<br><img alt="Pasted image 20241115072627.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20241115072627.png" style="width: 400px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Maximum speed

<br>The device was spun at 15Hz, or 900rpm
<br>Immediately after holding for 1 minute, the device was stopped
<br>Bulging could be seen on the membrane, but also the top acetate layer
<br>Further analysis will be made to estimate the pressure under those conditions to determine the maximum speed for various membrane sizes
<br>For a membrane with diameter of 16mm, no more than 1000rpm are recommended.

<br>Reciprocation is slow

<br>As shown in previous experiments, reciprocation, regardless of the membrane size, is slow

<br>Tune volume with membrane, tune flow rate with cross section

<br>As the membrane size is increased, more fluid is capable of entering the air chamber before a critical pressure is reached, when flow rate decreases fast
<br>If the issue is now the duration of experimentation, an increase of the cross section of channels could increase the flow rate

<br><img alt="Membrane_size_sim.png" src="lib/media/membrane_size_sim.png" style="width: 500px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Membrane size vs liquid in air chamber

<br>Same conditions, including velocity profile, remain the same, except the membrane radius
<br>As radius increases, the maximum amount of fluid increases
<br>Presumably, if max speed is held longer, bigger membranes would reach maximum volume at later times

<br><img alt="Channel_size_10.png" src="lib/media/channel_size_10.png" style="width: 500px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Emptying profile with change in channels dimensions

<br>For this figure, a membrane radius of 10mm was used, leaving all the other conditions the same, except for the channel depth
<br>Channel depth, currently, is given by the thickness of the PSA
<br>Change in width giving out the same cross section as these changes in depth give out the same results
<br>Change in cross section doesn't change the limit change of fluid (minimum volume for source chamber and maximum volume for air chamber)
<br>Change in cross section does change the flow rate, as an increase in cross section leads to more volume exiting and entering the chambers at a certain time

<br>Simulations confirm volume tuning and flow rate tuning
For the next week, it is proposed to find the optimal membrane size and channel width to overall increase the performance of the device, including reduction of time per reciprocation cycle.
]]></description><link>thesis-ii-3rd-semester/week-15-(nov-11-nov-15).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Thesis II - 3rd semester/Week 15 (Nov 11 - Nov 15).md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:16:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20241115072627.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20241115072627.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mario's Log for Thesis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Hello, everyone.<br>This will be where I will be submitting and recording whatever I do everyday for my master's thesis project. More specifically, I will be recording the activities mainly for the experimental part (since the main thing of the theoretical part is code, so that is easier) unless stated otherwise: whenever I make relevant changes in the code (relevant means that it changes the result) I will describe them on the corresponding day.<br>I will be dividing this in weeks and in each week, it will be divided into the different days, including weekends in some situations, in case I just get an idea during those days. Otherwise, it will mainly be composed of Monday - Friday.<br>Ideas, thoughts and/or conclusions from activities will be in italics, as something to take into account for future related activities.<br>Any suggestions in the changes of format or arrangement are welcome.]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 15:11:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>